Gabriel Anderson

andgate.github.io

github.com/andgate linkedin.com/in/andgate in

Objective

Highly skilled developer with 2 years of industry experience and 15 years of independent practice, seeking a frontend developer role where I can apply my ideation, relator, and strategic strengths, alongside my broad range of technical skills, to build awesome software that makes a difference in the world.

Experience

SMART Technologies

Seattle, WA

Frontend Software Developer

Aug. 2019 - Feb. 2021

- Served millions of customers on a frontend team responsible for supporting and expanding product capacity of the company's core solution, SMART Learning Suite Online.
- Attended daily team standups, collaborated with teammates over Azure DevOps and Slack.
- Projects were built to company standards, with Agile, Clean, and unit-tested modules.
- Authored technical design documentation on Confluence in collaboration with other development teams.
- Built and deployed projects using TeamCity, working closely with DevOps team to ensure projects were integrated into a large final product.
- Designed and developed an Android overlay widget manager, written in Kotlin with an MVVM architecture, powered by Kotlin Flow.
- Decomposed a bloated widget framework into a set of packages as NPM monorepo using Lerna, to enable students to use the framework.
- Built a iOS-style calculator widget with React.
- Participated in winning team place that won first place in the company hackathon, developing an elegant frontend solution in Vue under a limited time constraint.

Central Washington University

Ellensburg, WA

Undergraduate Directed Research

Apr. 2019 - Mar. 2019

- Under Dr. Arne Leitart, explored theories to develop more a efficient, parameterized approximation algorithm for the (Connected) r-Domination problem for unweighted and undirected graphs.
- New theories were explored on whiteboard and paper exclusively.

Central Washington University

Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

Teaching Assistant

Ellensburg, WA

- Graded homework assignments for Algorithm Analysis, taught by Dr. Boris Kovalerchuk.
- Graded homework assignments for Introduction to Graph Algorithms, taught by Dr. Arne Leitart.
- Assisted students during computer science lab hours for both classes.

Education

Central Washington University

Ellensburg, WA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Minor in Mathematics Graduated Magna Cum Laude Sept. 2017 - Mar. 2019

3.7 GPA

Projects

Alonzo

github.com/andgate/alonzo

• Lambda calculus interpreter and repl written in Haskell.

solid-orbit

github.com/andgate/solid-orbit

• Published NPM package with solid-js hooks and components that provide an oribt-js data-layer.

Mandelbulb Explorer

github.com/andgate/mandelbulb

- Raytracer with signed-distance field for mandelbulb written in C++ and glsl.
- SFML was used to provide interactivity.

Skills

- Languages:
 - o Proficient: Javascript, Typescript, CSS, HTML, JSON, Java, Kotlin, C, C++, Haskell
 - o Familiar: C#, Swift, Python, GLSL
- Frameworks: Node, React, Vue, Solid, Kotlin Flow, OpenGL
- Methodologies: Scrum, Clean, OOP, FP
- Technologies: Android, Git, NPM, Webpack, Babel, Lerna, Docker, Bash, Emacs, VSCode, NixOS